Nickson Kaigi | Curriculum Vitae

6677-00100, Nairobi Kenya □ +254 724 708 852 • ☑ nickaigi@gmail.com ♦ http://nickaigi.github.io/

Software engineer, with expansive knowledge of Python and JavaScript. Driven individual, with a background in Computer Science and vast experience developing and shipping software and data products. Currently pursuing a Master's of Science Degree in Computation Intelligence at The University of Nairobi.

Experience

FreeCast Inc.

Back-end Engineer
Back-end engineer.

September 2022 – Present

Sum Software Limited

Full Stack Engineer

November 2021 - July 2022

Was an engineer working on the Sumfully software. Sumfully is a Amazon Profit Analytics and Inventory Management Tool.

World Bank

Technical Consultant

December 2021 - January 2022

Working with The Data and Evidence for Justice Reform (DE JURE) and Development Impact Evaluation (DIME) units in the development of data-driven applications with the intention of studying, improving efficiency, quality and access to justice in developing countries.

Maxum Data

Lead Developer

June 2015 - October 2021

Lead developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration. I was responsible for design and development of the in-house analysis and reporting tool. I wrote Lua scripts that acted as an interface to a custom installation of Freeswitch. I wrote bash scripts that would analyse the production databases for changes that met a predetermined threshold, resulting in a call to action when the changes met the threshold. Wrote Python scripts that analysed spending on toll free and regular phone numbers and created monthly billing reports.

Domains Bot

Senior Python Developer

June 2015 – September 2015

Senior developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration.

SunUp Financial LLC (Balance Credit)

Senior Python Developer

May 2014 – January 2015

Senior developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration.

Soko Nairobi

Senior Python Developer

July 2013 - April 2014

Senior developer in charge of UX, Python and Android development for the suite of open source and enterprise tools that the company provided.

Sweet Relish

Senior Python Developer

December 2012 - July 2013

Python developer working with Django and jQuery mobile to deliver a mobile friendly version of the website.

Code Painters

Lead Software Developer

September – November 2012

Lead developer responsible for product development of various Python Django based web applications.

Apartment Rentals

Software Developer

April 2012

Python Django developer responsible for providing end-to-end Programming support.

MANteresting

Python/ Django Developer

March - April 2012

Python Django developer responsible for design and implementation of a REST based API.

Alliance Technologies

Nairobi

Software Engineer (intern)

September - December 2011

Engineering intern responsible for extending the A1ERP data dictionary and developing an android based prototype of the ERP.

Education

Academic Qualifications.....

University of Nairobi

Nairobi, Kenya

MSc Computation Intelligence, Completed Coursework. Thesis in Progress

2014-Present

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Nairobi, Kenya

BSc Computer Science, Second Class Honors, Upper Division

2008–2012

Menengai High School

Nakuru, Kenya

KCSE

2003–2006

Technical and Personal skills

• **Programming Languages:** Proficient in: Python, JavaScript, TEX Also basic ability with: C/C++.

Interests and extra-curricular activity

- I enjoy the game of Chess
- O I am an avid reader of fiction, high fantasy, biographical, and historical/historical fiction books

References

O Up to 3 references available on request